MARTIN ZERBIB

TECHNOLOGY EVANGELIST

martinzerbib@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/martinzerbib 07867787693

Nationality: French

Passionate technology advocate with both consumer and enterprise experience in data-driven technologies.

Overview	Technology Driven	Web Development	Customer Facing
	Able to learn and adapt quickly to new technologies and programming languages and apply them effectively.	Development of web applications for demos, proof of concepts and production, using a wide variety of languages and frameworks.	Experience in delivering workshops and presentations both to large audiences as well as to C-Level executives.
Technical Skills	Javascript/Jquery	Business Intelligence/Data Analytics	Linux
	Python	Enterprise Search	BigQuery/Snowflake/Redshift/MySQL/SQL
	Ruby	Presentations/Speaking	Java/Swift/PHP/Apex/C/C++/.NET

Experience

Looker-London

April 2017 - Present

Enterprise Sales Engineer

Looker harnesses the power of SQL, integrating data into the daily workflows of users to create a uniquely powerful data analytics platform that helps companies get real value and make data-driven decisions.

Established technical leader for the EMEA team, bringing and developing some of the largest Looker deployments in Europe and architecting embedded analytics solutions to serve tens of thousands of data consumers.

Building Looker's enterprise presence across the UK and France, driving Looker adoption and advising large businesses on their data analytics strategy.

Driving data democratization across teams and departments, by advising on data strategy and best practices.

Devising customer's data analytics solution by building upon Looker's SQL based semantic layer. Advising on other parts of the stack - Architecture, ETL, Data Warehousing

Splunk-London

October 2015 - April 2017

Enterprise Pre-Sales Consultant

Splunk is a market-leading data platform for Operational Intelligence, enabling users to search, monitor, analyze and visualize all of their event and log data.

Driving the technical element to sell complex enterprise software solutions to large enterprise customers. Also acting as subject matter expert for Security as well as Big Data.

Delivered consultative presentations, demonstrations and workshops to help prospects understand how Splunk addresses their technical and business requirements, around a wide range of Usecases: Security, IT Operations, Business Analytics, Internet

Deployed Proof of Concept solutions and Built custom demos and presentations around a prospect's requirements Representing Splunk at many tradeshows and events, such as IPExpo, InfoSec, Strata

HP Software Big Data- San Francisco

October 2013 - September 2015

Developer Evangelist

Working on the Haven Platform, a combination of Cloud and On Premise solution for unstructured data analytics and search (IDOL), and big data analytics (Vertica). <u>IDOLOnDemand.com</u>, <u>Vertica OnDemand</u>
Developed Evangelist strategy; initiated developer events, collaborating with local organizers; built a developer community;

responsible for technical writing of API references; documentation and presentations; developed applications, client libraries, demos and code examples; public speaking, media engagement, event coordination.

Sample work: Video: Face Recognition Nerf gun

Notable events attended: Mobile World Congress '15 (Talk), Developer Week '15 (Talk), API World '14 (Talk), Topcoder Open '14 (Judge)

HP Autonomy - London

Senior Pre-Sales Technical Consultant

July 2011 - October 2013

Led pre-sales and post-sales engagements in Europe in the matters of enterprise search, social media analytics and web content management.

Provided subject matter expertise, project guidance, and consulting leadership to diverse clientele on HP Autonomy products along with other adjacent technologies

Multiple overlaps with professional services and delivery due to strong technical skills, in charge of projects from sales opportunity to delivery

Notable projects:

- User targeted recommendation engine for a top 2000 alexa rank News site.
- Distributed social media analytics solution ingesting and analysing multi million tweets, news articles and intranet docs each
- Multiple enterprise search solutions: Sizing, Architecture, Design, Implementation, Data Ingestion, Optimization

UBS Investment Bank- London

London, June 2009 - September 2009

IT Intern

Java intern, worked on banking solutions and products, participated in planning, design, implementation and decision making.

Imperial College London

Undergraduate teaching assistant

2008 - 2010

Taught tutorial sessions and marked Mathematics-based coursework.

Holland Park School

2008

Mathematics Teaching Assistant

Assisted with, taught and created lesson plans for KS3 and KS4 Mathematics students.

Education

Imperial College London

MSci Joint Mathematics and Computer Science, 2.1

2006 - 2010

Languages

- Native French
- Fluent English